（ノノハ）イワシの骨。
Sardine bones.
ダイコンの葉っぱ。
Radish leaves.
古くなったタマネギ。　隠し味に
大量の唐辛子を入れれば…→
An old onion.
And lots of chili peppers to cover the taste.
ノノハスイーツ　デススペシャルの生地が完成。
The Nonoha Sweets Death Special dough is complete.
That's strong!
強烈！
これくらい　ショックがあれば…。
This much shock should do it.
心の声
今までは　クッキー１個で
元に戻ってくれてたのに…。
Until now, a single cookie would do the trick.
あのときは持ってたスイーツ
心の声
全部　食べさせても→
Back then, I made Kaito eat all the cookies I had with me,
なかなか　いつものカイトに
心の声
戻ってくれなかった…。
but he still didn't return to his usual self.
なんだか　カイトは　どんどん　私の
知らないカイトになっていくみたい。
It's like he's turning into someone I don't know.
今　カイトに元気あげられるのは
私だけでしょう！
I'm the only one who can cheer Kaito up right now!
しょげてちゃ　ダメじゃん！
（呼び鈴）
I can't be feeling down!
カイト！　取って置きのスイーツ完成！
Kaito, I brought you some sweets!
ちょっと実験　ううん
味見してみて。
Wanna experi— I mean, give them a taste?
The door's open, right? I'm coming in.
鍵　開いてるよね。　入るよ。
（ミハル）えっと…　カイトさんに
何か御用ですか？
Um...
Do you want something from Kaito?
あっ？！…　誰？！
Who are you?
kimi no nounai he shinnyuu nemutteiru sukima ni
I infiltrate your brain while you're sleeping.
Baby, open the gate!
fukuzatsu sugi sekyuriti kakusareru to abakitaku naru
The security's too tough, but I want to expose what's hidden.
barabara ni chirabatteiru pasuwado wo hiroi atsume
I gather the pieces of the shattered password.
kakushin ni sematte iku sono shoutai wo misete
I get close to the core. Show me who you really are!
kantan ni kuria dekinai saki nante motto yomenai
I can't clear it easily. I can't even see what lies ahead.
kaidoku fukanou sumairu kikenna pazuru
Your indecipherable smile is a hazardous puzzle.
rokku sareta doa aru nara zutto tataite miru beki kazana hiraku wa
When you see a locked door, you should just hit it until a crack opens.
eien ni hodokenai nazo nanka wa nai
There's no mystery that lasts forever!
makiokosu, it's a supernova
I made it, it's a supernova!
tobikiri shigekitekina hirameki wo agemashou
Let's flash so bright it'd hurt!
Misskey-Misskey La-Tu-Ma
yume no naka it's a supernova
In my dreams, it's a supernova!
watashi wa sou brain diver
Yeah, I'm the brain diver!
kimi ga sagashi motometeru kotae ni nareru made
Until I can find the answer you're looking for...
Brain diver!
Proof of the Traitor
ギャモン君の妹さん？！
逆之上ミハルって言います。
Gammon's little sister?
I'm Sakanoue Miharu.
いつも　お兄ちゃん…　いえ
兄が　お世話になってます。
Thank you being there for my brother.
（カイト）信じらんねえよな。
なぜに　あの兄貴から　この子が…。
It's hard to believe, huh?
How does a guy like him get a sister like you?
よく言われます。　っていうか　兄が
私を産んだ訳じゃないんですけど。
People say that a lot. But it's not like we're twins or anything.
（おなかの鳴る音）
う～っ。　すいません。
Sorry... I haven't eaten anything since last night.
きのうの夜から御飯食べてなくて。
（２人）えっ？！
あっ　すごくおいしい！
うそ？！
These are really good!
No way!
やだ！　うまっ！　ああ～　この
たぐいまれなる料理の才能が→
Hey, they are good!
My legendary cooking skills ruined my plan.
私のもくろみを邪魔したのね。
もくろみ？
What plan?
ねぇ。　レシピ教えてあげようか。
びっくりすると思うよ！
Hey, would you like to know the recipe? You'll be surprised!
ああ　いえ　私
料理　大の苦手なんです。
Sorry, but I'm really no good at cooking.
御飯の支度も　いつも
お兄ちゃんがやってくれて。
I can't even cook rice, so my brother does that too.
（２人）マジっ？！　あの顔で？！
You're kidding!
With that face?
う～っ。　顔で　お料理するわけじゃ
ありませんから。
It's not like he's cooking with his face.
私たち　ギャモン君のこと
あんまり知らなかったんだね。
We didn't know much about Gammon, I guess.
まさか　こんな妹さんがいて
そんな家庭的な面があるなんて…。
I never thought he'd have a little sister like you
and even be in charge of the household...
けど　心配だよね。
You're worried, right? He hasn't been home since yesterday, has he?
ギャモン君　きのうから
帰ってきてないんでしょう。
あぁ　お兄ちゃんが帰らないのは
珍しいことじゃないんです。
It's not a rare occurrence when he doesn't come home,
ただ　いつもは　必ず
連絡をくれるのに…。
but he always at least calls or texts me.
それと　けさ　郵便受けを見たら
お兄ちゃんから私宛てに…。
And when I checked the mail this morning,
there was this letter from him.
何　これ？
小切手じゃん！
What's this?
It's a check!
小切手！　初めて見た。　ハハハッ。
何？　このゼロの数！
A check? It's first time I've seen one! What are all these zeros?
一　十　百　千　万…。
Tens, hundreds, thousands, ten thousands...
あ～！　もう食べられません。
This is more than I could eat!
きのう　何か変わったこと
ありませんでしたか？
Did something strange happen to him yesterday?
お兄ちゃんに。　もし　知っていたら
教えてほしいんです。
If you know anything, please tell me where he could be!
どこに行ったか。
あっ。
My, oh my.
（ダイスマン）これは　これは。
（メイズ）ずいぶんと　すてきな→
What a wonderful guest we have.
お客さまですこと。
（ギャモン）姫川エレナの紹介で来た。
Let Gammon join,
pwetty pwease!
I'm here on Himekawa Elena's invitation.
ルーク・盤城・クロスフィールドに会いたい。
I want to meet Rook Banjo Crossfield.
As if he has time for a lame little Solver like you.
ルーク様が　雑魚ソルヴァーなんかに
会うわけないじゃん。
How did you get through security?
どんなインチキ使って
セキュリティー　くぐってきたわけ？
正式オファーだ。　どけ。
はぁ？
It's an official offer. Out of my way.
潰すぞ。
潰してみれば？
I'll crush you.
Try it.
今日の俺は　ソルヴァーじゃねえ。
I'm not a Solver today!
I'm here as a Giver just like you!
てめえらと同じ　ギヴァーとして
ここに来た。→
ギヴァー勝負で　俺の相手になれると
思ってんのか？　雑魚以下ども。
Do you think you can match me, you lamer than lame little Givers.
しょうがないね。
じゃ　軽く遊んでやっか？
うん。
Guess we've got no choice. Let's have some fun.
（ミハル）私たちには両親がいません。
代わりに私を→
We don't have parents. My brother raised me in their place.
ここまで育ててくれたのは
お兄ちゃんなんです。
幼いころから
パズルを作るのが大好きで→
He's loved making puzzles since he was little,
その才能を見いだされ
パズル作家となって→
so when he was discovered and became a puzzle author,
私を　何不自由なく
養い育ててくれました。
he was able to support us financially without a problem.
でも　気づけば　お金のために
パズルを作るようになっていて→
But then he started making puzzles just for the money,
そして　いつしか　暗い顔に…。
and his face turned darker and darker...
でも最近　また　お兄ちゃんに
笑顔が戻ってきたの！
But lately I've seen him smiling again!
"Kaito's so friggin' annoying! He pisses me off!"
「カイトは　うぜえ！
カイトは　気に食わねえ！」って。
そういうお兄ちゃんは
生き生きしてて…。
And so on... He was really lively!
あと寝言じゃ
いつも「ノノハ　ノノハ！」って。
And he's always saying, "Nonoha, Nonoha!" in his sleep.
だから　ひょっとして
えっ？　私？！
お二人なら　知ってるかなって。
Me?
So I wondering if you two knew anything.
ごめんね。　もし分かったら
すぐに連絡する。
Sorry. You'll be the first to know if we learn anything.
お願いします。　じゃあ　私
お兄ちゃんが帰ってくるまでは→
Thank you.
I'll try to hold out on pre-packaged food from the store until he gets back.
コンビニ弁当で頑張ります！
どこへ行っちゃったんだろう？
ギャモン君。
Where could he have gone?
カイトと対戦したあと
何か　あったのかな？
Did something happen after you fought?
知らねえよ。
うっ。　心配じゃないの？
How should I know?
Aren't you worried?
やつが　何しようが　やつの勝手だ。
そんな言い方…。
It's none of my business what he does.
Don't put it like that!
お～い　カイト。
あっ。
Earth to Kaito!
どうしたの？
いいや　何でもねえ。
What's wrong?
It's nothing.
僕のパズルは　こいつ。
サイコロで　マス目を埋める。
This is my puzzle.
Fill the grid with dice.
ただし　縦横　各列に並ぶ
サイコロの目が重なっちゃ　ダメ。
However, each number can be present in each line and row only once.
赤で区切ってある
ブロックの内側も　そう。
The same goes for the areas of six blocks divided by the red lines;
同じ目のサイコロがあっちゃ　ダメ。
どう？　シンプル　かつ難解！
each number can only be there once.
What do you think? It's simple, yet difficult!
最高に美しい作品だと思わね？
フン…。
Don't you think it's the perfect beauty?
Hey, stop that! You're going to mess...
おい！　勝手なこと　すんなよ。
それじゃ　パズルが…。
（フンガ）成立してる！
何っ？！
It still works.
What?
He even raised the difficulty as high as possible.
しかも　難易度を
ぎりぎりにまで上げた！
ヘ　ヘェ～　やるじゃん。
Not bad.
So this is your level?
この程度で感心か？
うっ　はっ。
ＰＯＧのレベルも　たかが知れてんな。
Is this what I should expect from the POG?
せ　正解だ。
Correct.
サイコロの横っ面も
目が重なってない！
It's even correct on the sides!
しかも　４面とも！
All four of them!
通してもらうぜ。
I'm going inside.
（壁の開く音）
待ちなさい！
Hold it right there.
今度は　私が相手！
あっ？　おっ。
I'm your next opponent.
何だ　こりゃ？
ウフフッ。
What's this?
迷わずにゴールしてごらんなさい。
Head directly to the goal.
そのコースを　なぞれば
すてきな名前が…。
If you follow the path, you'll see a wonderful name.
あ～ん？！
「Ｍ　Ａ　Ｚ　Ｅ」　メイズ。
ひょっとして　あんたの名前か？
M-A-Z-E.
Maze. Is that your name?
だが　こうすれば…。
But if I do this...
ちょっと　何やってるの？
Hey, what are you doing?
あっ！…　ア　アメイズド！
Amazed!
文字どおり　驚いただろう。
I bet you're amazed.
つ　次は　私が？！
（ビショップ）「もう　いい」。
I-I'm next.
No need.
（ビショップ）私がお相手しましょう。
（３人）ビショップ様！
I will escort you.
Sir Bishop!
中ボス　登場ってか？
Onto the mid-level boss?
ミハルちゃん　かわいかったよね！
Miharu's so cute, isn't she?
もし　私が部屋に来なかったら
ひょっとして？！
What if I hadn't come over?
Maybe...!
アホかよ。
待って！
You're insane.
Hey, wait!
（エレナ）ノノハ　ぽろり～ん！
カイト　ぺろり～ん！
Nonoha, love! Kaito, love!
お久しぶりり～ん。
Love time no see!
お待たせしました。
あぁ。
どうぞ　こちらへ。
I apologize for the wait.
This way, please.
おい　ビショップさんよ。
俺のバイク　どうしたんだ？
Hey, Bishop-dude, where's my bike?
少々　細工を
させていただきました。
I took the liberty of redesigning it a bit.
何っ？！
ご心配なく。
What?!
Worry not.
走行に支障はありません。
It will have no effect on its controls.
白黒ハッキリ勝負がつく
大舞台を用意しました。
I just prepared the stage to clearly decide who wins.
卑怯なマネは　しねえだろうな。
もちろん。
I hope you're not planning anything cowardly.
Of course not.
（ビショップ）
互いのバイクが　背後を取り合い
相手を撃破する　アイアンホース　ドッグファイト。
The Iron Horse Dog Fight. You are to come up behind your opponent and shoot.
このサーキットで
勝負していただきましょう。
We will be competing in this circuit.
なあ！　あれは　俺の…。
That's my bike!
That is your starting point.
（ビショップ）あそこが
あなたのスタート位置になります。
ルールを説明しましょう。
Allow me explain the rules.
これが　サーキットの全体像です。
This is an image of the circuit.
コースは　５つのレーンに
分かれています。
There are five lanes in total.
バイクは２台とも　一定速度を
保つようになっていて→
The bikes move at the same speed,
相手に追いつくためには　レーンチェンジ
ポイントを駆使しなくてはなりません。
so you need to use the lane change points to catch up to your opponent.
これを動かすと　隣のレーンに
移動することができます。
When you use them, you will move to the next lane.
同様に　相手の進路を
強制的に変えることも可能です。
You can also force your opponent to change their path.
ただし　一度動かしたポイントは
自由に元に戻すことはできません。
However, once you use a change point, you cannot move it again.
コース全体で動かせるポイントは
最大１０か所。
There can only be ten gates open at the same time.
１１か所目のポイントを
動かしたときに→
If you open an eleventh, the first one will automatically return to its original position.
１つ目のポイントが
自動的に元に戻ります。
どっちが操作してもか？
そうです。
Doesn't matter which player opens it?
Indeed.
２人合わせて　１０か所です。
２台のバイクには　同じ高さで→
It is a total of ten.
Both bikes are equipped with a lightgun and a tail sensor.
ライト・ガンとテールセンサーが
装着されています。
そして　どちらかが背後を取り→
If a player gets behind the other and flashes at his tail sensor, it is the end.
相手のテールセンサーに　フラッシュライトを
撃ち込めば　ジ・エンド。
（ギャモン）ジ・エンド？
バイクには爆薬が仕掛けてあります。
The end?
The bikes are wired with explosives.
（ギャモン）上等だ。
確かに　ハッキリ白黒つくぜ。
Perfect. This will give us a clear winner then.
（ビショップ）「レーン・チェンジポイントの操作は
左ハンドルのリモコンに→
You can control a lane change point by entering its number into the controller at your left handle.
数字を入力して行ってください」。
（ビショップ）準備は　よいですか？
（ギャモン）「ああ　いつでも　いいぜ」。
Are you ready?
Yeah! Anytime.
１つ聞かせてください。
Let me ask you one thing.
（ビショップ）「どうして　ルーク様の
申し出を受ける気に？」。
Why are you requesting an audience with Sir Rook?
証明するためだ。
（ビショップ）「証明？」。
To prove it.
Prove?
大門カイトより　俺の方が
優れてるってことをな。
That I'm better than Daimon Kaito.
ＰＯＧのギヴァーになって
俺は　やつをぶっ潰す！
I'll become a POG Giver and crush him!
That is regrettable.
それは困りましたね。
彼は　我々の行く末にとって
絶対　不可欠な存在なのですが…。
He is indispensable to the reaching of our goal.
（ギャモン）「俺様が代わってやる」。
あなたに　そんな力があると？
I'll take his place then.
Can you really do that?
Isn't that why your boss called me?
（ギャモン）「だから　おめえのボスは
俺を呼んだんだろう」。
I see. However, I am not as sharp as Sir Rook,
なるほど。　しかし　私は　ルーク様ほど
聡明ではないもので…。
その力　自身で確かめてみるまでは
納得できません。
so I need to confirm your prowess for myself.
なら　今から思い知らせてやらあ！
Then I'll show you right now!
ギャモン君がＰＯＧに？！
ホントなの？　エレナさん。
Gammon went to the POG?
Is that true, Elena?
What would I gain by lying to you?
私が　あんたらに　ウソついて
なんか　得でもあったっけ？
なんなんだ？　そりゃ。
ルーク様が　オファーを出したの。
What the hell's going on?
Sir Rook made him an offer.
ルークが？！
えぇ。
Rook did?!
But it was Galileo who accepted it.
ただし　受諾したのは　ガリレオ自身。
なるほどなぁ。
I see.
ゆうべ　やつが用意したパズル
どうりで　大仕掛けだと思ったぜ。
I figured last night's puzzle wasn't something that could be prepared in an afternoon.
でも　どうして教えてくれたの？
まあ　ちょっとね。
But why are you telling us?
Well, because... he's changed a lot recently.
前に会ったときと　ずいぶん
雰囲気が違ってたから。
私が好きだった　あいつとは…。
えっ？　何？！
He's not the guy I love anymore...
What did you just say?
うっ。　と　とにかく伝えたからね！
A-Anyway, I told you!
あとは連れ戻すでも
改心させるでも→
You may as well try to convince him to come back if you want.
どうにでも　するといいわ。
仲間だっけ？
Aren't you his friends?
小学生じゃあるまいし　バッカみたい。
俺には関係ねぇ。
You're not kids anymore. It's stupid.
It's none of my business.
カイト！
Kaito!
ＰＯＧでも　どこでも　行きてえんなら
勝手に行きゃあいい。
If he wants to go join the POG or whatever, then let him.
止める筋合いなんて　ねえよ。
I don't have the right to stop him.
心の声
やつの尻に食らいついて　ライト・ガンを
お見舞いすりゃ　いいわけだが→
I should just stick to his ass and give him a taste of my lightgun.
心の声
当然　追いつかなきゃならねえ。
Of course, I gotta catch up first.
両者　同じスピードに
心の声
固定されてるとなると→
Both bikes are locked at the same speed,
心の声
勝負の鍵は　いかに
やつを　周回距離の長くなる→
so the key is to force him onto a longer track.
外へと追いやるかだ。
心の声
That's where this comes into play.
（ギャモン）そこで　こいつの出番か！
始めましたね。
It's started.
And now I'll go inwards to the shorter...
そして　俺は　周回距離の短くなる
内側へ…。　うっ？！
俺も外へ出された！
He guided me out as well?
内側のレーンに入りやがった。
そうは　させるか！
He went to an inside lane. I won't let you!
Take this!
Now, get your ass back here!
さあ　俺の前に出てこい！
ありがとう！　送ってくれて。
別に　お礼なんて　いいのよ。
Thanks for the ride.
No need for thanks.
どうせ　この道
通るとこだったんだし。
I was heading this way anyway.
で　あなた　この先　どうするの？
この先って？
What are you going to do now?
What do you mean?
あぁ　今からカイトと　食材調達に…。
We're going to buy some food...
そういうことじゃなくて。
うっ。
That's not what I mean.
あなたも　そろそろ
彼から離れた方がいいかも。
It might be time for you to get away from him as well.
うっ。　エレナさんまで　そんな…。
死にたくないでしょう？
Even you're saying that, Elena?
Do you want to die?
Look, it's Elena!
（通行人Ａ）ねぇねぇ　あれ　エレナかも。
（通行人Ｂ）本当　姫川じゃん。
チェ。
Really, it's Himekawa!
あっ　カイト！
みんな！　今月　リリースのエレナの新曲→
Hey, Kaito!
Hey guys! I'm releasing my new song,
Kaito, wait!
「恋のパズルを解いて」
応援　よろぴろり～ん！
"Solve the Puzzle of Love" this month!
I hope you all love it!
じゃ　またね　エレナさん。
待って！
See you later, Elena!
Wait.
あげる。
あっ。
It's yours.
じゃ　まあ　せいぜい足手まといに
ならないようにすることね。
Try not to be too much of a burden.
何してんのよ。
早く出しなさいよ！
What are you doing? Get going already!
ぷりり～ん！
カイト！
Kaito!
あいつも　なんか変わった。
She's changed too.
カイト！
Kaito!
もう　どこ行っちゃったの？
カイト～！
Where did he go? Kaito!
まさか　ホントに足手まといだとか
思われてたりして…。
Does she really think I'm just a burden?
ひどい！　見てなさいよ。
Watch! I can solve a puzzle like this is if I try!
私だって　本気出せば
こんなパズルの　１つや　２つ…。
う～ん。　はい！　できません！
Okay, I'm still hopeless!
カイト～！
Kaito!
（ビショップ）
「あなたも知っているはずです。→
I believe you are aware that Daimon Kaito is a child of the Phi Brain.
大門カイトが　ファイ・ブレインの
子供であることを」。
学園長が言ってたぜ。
俺も　そうだと。
The principal told me. He said I'm one too.
ファイ・ブレインになる資格が
あるってな！
I have the possibility to achieve the Phi Brain!
それは　彼の持論にすぎません。
That is merely his opinion.
The fact that you don't have the Armband of Orpheus is proof.
その証拠に　あなたは
オルペウスの腕輪を持っていない。
（ギャモン）「んなもん
こっちから　願い下げだ！」。
Don't give me that crap!
あの腕輪に飲み込まれたカイトは
見てらんねえくらい→
When that thing took control of Kaito,
he was so pathetic I couldn't even watch!
みっともなかったぜ！
However, he obtained a great power through that.
（ビショップ）「しかし　それと引き換えに
彼は　更なるパワーを得た」。
オルペウスの腕輪があればこそ　人は
ファイ・ブレインへ近づくことができる。
With the Armband of Orpheus, one becomes closer to the Phi Brain.
You're coming inside now?
次で入ってくるか？！
What a shame. That was a quick escape.
惜しかった。
うまく逃げましたね…。
心の声
（ギャモン）
相手の進路のことだけじゃねえ。
It's not only about predicting the opponent's path,
I have to consider which gates are going to close first too!
次に　どのポイントが
心の声
元に戻るかまで　記憶してやがる。
こうかな。
This way...?
じゃなくて　こう？
No, like this...?
あれ？　解けてる。
Huh? It's solved!
It's my first time...
初めて解けた…。
ハハッ。　私　パズル解いたよ。
I solved a puzzle! Kaito!
カイト！
（ビショップ）「神のパズルとは　人類を
更なる高みの次元へといざなう→
The Divine Puzzle will lead mankind to a new dimension.
いわば究極にして　至高の扉…。→
You could consider it the door to absolute knowledge.
Do you not believe it is foolish of a lowly, ordinary human
それを　たかが　一介の凡人風情が
己の力だけで解こうなどとは→
愚かすぎる　うぬぼれだとは
思いませんか？」。
to think that he could solve it by his own power?
どうしました？　先ほどから
無意味なポイントばかりを操作して…。
What's wrong? You're aimlessly switching the gates.
ラッキーパンチでも狙っているのですか？
Are you going for a lucky hit?
（ビショップ）
「無駄ですよ。　オルペウスの腕輪も
持たないあなたに　そんな奇跡…」。
It's futile. Without the Armband of Orpheus, you cannot...
（ギャモン）「偉そうに　小難しいこと
言ってるけどよ→
Go on about the Armband all you want!
オルペウスの腕輪ってのも　大したこと
ねえんじゃねえか？！」。
この大天才の俺様を　まだ
見つけられてねえんだからな！
It must suck if it couldn't even find an amazing genius like me!
Take it!
食らえ！
その程度で　追い詰めたとでも？
あなたなど　しょせん…。
You were hoping to catch me with that?
You're a thousand years too young!
しまった！
No!
もらった！
Gotcha!
No way...
ま　まさか…　あの無意味な
レーンチェンジの間に　トラップを…。
He constructed a trap during all those pointless lane changes?
（ギャモン）チェックメイトだ。
あっ！
Checkmate.
誰にも俺の邪魔はさせねぇ。
I won't let anyone to get in my way.
天の定めだろうと
なんだろうとな！
Not even your divine bullshit.
ハァ。　認めよう。
I must admit defeat.
私の完敗だ。
これで　足手まといなんて
言わせないんだから。
Now you can't say I'm just a burden!
（呼び鈴）
お～い！　カイト！　解いたよ　カイト！
Hey, Kaito! I solved it!
あれ？　まだ帰ってないの？　カイト！
Huh? You're still not home?
Kaito? Are you here or not?
居る？　居ない？
If you're not, then say so!
居ないんだったら
「居ない」って言って！
おい！　カイト！　お～い！　居る？
Hey, Kaito! Hey! Are you there?
（ルーク）
大門カイトを超えたいなどという
些末な願いは君にふさわしくない。
The primitive wish to exceed Daimon Kaito is not fit for you.
何だと！
What?!
君にはオルペウスの腕輪など無くとも→
Even without the Armband of Orpheus,
神のパズルに挑戦する力が
あるかもしれないと言ってるんだ。
you may have the ability to challenge the Divine Puzzle.
何？！
君には　その資格がある。
What?
You have the ability. The ability to solve the Divine Puzzle,
神のパズルを解き　神の書を開いて
全能の力を　手に入れる資格がね。
and become omnipotent through the Divine Revelations.
全能の力…。
Omnipotence?
Now, come to me!
さあ　私と共に…
この階段を上れば→
Once you climb these stairs, there will be no turning back.
もう　あとには引き返せない。
tsukue no ue de umareta sekai
This world born on my table.
ichiban saki ni kimi ni misetakatta
I wanted you to see it first.
karappo no heya sotto nukedashite hashiri hajimeteta
I sneaked out of the empty room and started to run.
iki hazamasete oka wo noboru to
As I got to the top of the hill, out of breath,
kimi ga saki ni tsuite matteita ne
you were already there waiting for me.
takusan no hajimete kimi to mitsuketa takaramono datta
It was the first of many treasures we would find together.
kanashisa de afureta toki wa
When sorrow was overflowing in me,
nanimo iwazu ni tada soba ni ite kureta ne
you just silently stayed by my side.
ima de mo wasurenai yo
I still haven't forgotten that.
mata aou ne yakusoku wo shiyou
Let's promise we'll meet again.
kie wa shinai ano hi no sayonara
The goodbye of that day we'll never forget.
boku no subete kimi ga kureta michi
All I have I got from you,
zutto kokoro no naka hikaru yo
and it will all shine in my heart forever.